hmy.com 2019-07-08

# Privacy Policy | HMY Yacht Sales

## Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been created to better serve those who are concerned with how their information is being used in online environments with HMY Yacht Sales. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect and use your information in accordance with our website and additional digital initiatives.

## What personal information do we collect from the people that interact with our website, blog, social media, boat chat, listing service (on our website) and email channels?

When entering your information on our website through a form, reviewing listings, or engaging in BoatChat, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, phone number and applicable business-related details so HMY can better help you with your customer experience. It is our job to better understand our customers, so we can provide a world-class experience.

## When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you visit online listings (Yachtworld, Boats.com, BoatTrader, MarineSource, Yatco or similar boat listing services), subscribe to a newsletter, interact with our social media channels, fill out a form on our website, social, or listing service or engage with our BoatChat chat functionality.

## How do we use your information?

We use the information collected on our website and through other digital channels to help provide all users with a better HMY Yacht Sales user experience and send out business related communications through email, mail, social media, digital remarketing through Google as well as print and in-person communications. Please know, HMY is only gathering information to help us provide an exceptional experience for our customer.

## SSL certificate

We do use SSL on our website to help protect our information and our users' information.

## Do we use 'cookies'?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a website, social media, digital ad service (Google or Facebook) or related service provider like BoatChat use to help collect basic user information. Cookies transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (only if you allow) that enables the website or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We also use cookies for Boat Chat, Facebook and Google remarketing to help provide our users with a more enjoyable yacht search experience. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf. You can choose to have your computer communicate with you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to "turn off all cookies". You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookie settings. 

## Third Party Disclosure

HMY does not sell your personal information to any outside sources or partners. Third Party website development, CRM and business partners do have access to collected data. However, they are only using it under the direction of HMY for standard business purposes. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. 

## Google

Google's advertising requirements can be summed up by Google's Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. [Learn More](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/6008942?hl=en&visit_id=1-636584507862593455-3294431178&rd=1)

## We have implemented the following

HMY along with third-party vendors, such as Google Analytics, Adwords, Social media, email service providers, BoatChat, Boat Listing Services and other digital initiatives and CRM functions we use for standard business operations may use first-party cookies to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website and operations.

## Facebook

HMY does engage with Facebook social media advertising that serves advertisements to social media constituents and links them to our website. We collect website visitor trends through Facebook. We also engage with Facebook advertising and boosting to help us communicate more effectively to our wide audience.

## Opting-out

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt-out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

## California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law's reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. [Learn More](https://consumercal.org/about-cfc/cfc-education-foundation/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa-3/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf)

## According to CalOPPA we agree to the following

Users can visit our site anonymously. Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our footer section. Users will not be notified of privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page; however, they can visit our Privacy Policy page at any time to see when our policy was last updated.

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing HMY website administrator [marketing@hmy.com](mailto:marketing@hmy.com)
  * By contacting us by phone 561-277-4200

## COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation's consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children's privacy and safety online. We do not specifically market to children under 13.

## Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in-line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur: We will notify the users via email as soon as possible.

## CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations. HMY mainly uses MailChimp for commercial email use which complies with CANSPAM opt-out regulations.

We collect your email address in order to:

  * Send general business and transactional communications, customer service, communications and marketing information, inquiry responses and/or other requests or questions gathered and handled through digital channels mentioned in this document.
  * We may also send customers additional information related to your request
  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send general communications, and marketing emails and digital responses to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:

  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at [marketing@hmy.com](mailto:marketing@hmy.com) and we will promptly remove you from ALL email correspondence.
